You must return to your universe.
I must have my Captain back.
I shall operate the Transporter.
You have two minutes and ten seconds.
For that time I have something to say...
How long before the Halkan prediction
of Galactic revolt is realized?
Approximately 240 years.
The inevitable outcome?
The Empire shall be
overthrown, of course.
The illogic of waste, Mr. Spock.
A waste of lives, potential,
resources, time.
I submit to you that
your Empire is illogical...
Because it cannot endure.
I submit...
That you...
...are illogical...
To be a willing part of it.
You have 1 minute
and 23 seconds.
If change is inevitable,
predictable, beneficial...
Doesn't logic demand that
you be a part of it?
One man cannot summon the future.
But one man can change the present.
Be the Captain of this Enterprise, Mr. Spock.
Find a logical reason for sparing
the Halkans and make it stick.
Push till it gives...
You can defend yourself better
than any man in the fleet.
Captain! Get in the chamber!
What about it, Spock?
A man must also have the power.
In my cabin...
...is a device that will
make you invincible.
Indeed.
What will it be?
Past or future? Tyranny or freedom?
It's up to you.
It is time.
In every revolution there
is one man with a vision.
[ENERGIZING]
Captain Kirk, I shall consider it.
[ANGRY RANTS]
KIRK:
What the devil is going
on, Mr. Spock?
It is agreeable to see
you again, Captain.
It appears you were
temporarily interchanged...
...with counterparts from
a parallel universe.
Most of the crew is unaware
of these events.
I know what happened, Spock.
I wanna know why.
The ion storm created a
transporter irregularity...
Resulting in a transposition of the
landing party's quantum wave signature.
Chief Kyle was at the controls.
He has been disciplined.
[CHUCKLES]
He'd better have been.
- Mr. Scott.
- Sir?
Check the transporter relays.
Make sure this doesn't happen again.
I trust the Halkans have
been dealt with?
Apparently I have to do
everything myself, don't I.
Kirk to Bridge.
Is the Halkan capital city in firing range?
Coming around again
in 4 minutes, sir.
Good.
On my way.
MOREAU:
Welcome back, Captain.
See you in my quarters.
Captain on the Bridge.
Lieutenant.
Get the Halkans on the screen.
Where's my navigator?
Captain...?
Mr. Chekov...
Ensign Chekov.
Return to your station immediately.
It is merciful of you to forgive Mr. Chekov
after his assassination attempt.
I agree the agony booth made
a sufficient impression.
What's the hold up, Lieutenant?
Do you have them?
Council-leader Tharn standing by.
Your time has run out.
I'm tired of playing with you.
This is no game, Captain Kirk.
Oh, no.
It's not.
You have 30 seconds to relinquish
your dilithium crystals.
Or this face is the
last one you'll see.
That would be most unwise, Captain.
But we are prepared to die to
protect what we hold dear.
Have it your way.
Start the countdown. Ready phasers.
Wait...
Load photon torpedo tubes.
Full spread.
SPOCK:
Captain...
The Halkans have no
planetary defense grid.
A torpedo barrage is unnecessary.
The radiation fallout would likely
annihilate the entire population.
Likely...
Fitting isn't it? An example to
all who defy the Empire.
Captain.
If I may...
Logic dictates that the survival
of the Halkan civilization...
...could prove profitable for the
Empire for many years to come.
You could be the first to set
the precedent of diplomacy...
...that could yield long-term benefits.
I would recommend lesser measures.
You've given me much to
think about, Mr. Spock.
Fire.
KIRK (VO):
Space...
The final conquest.
These are the voyages of
the Starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission...
To discover and subjugate
strange new worlds.
To advance our dominion and
vanquish all who stand against us.
To conquer the Galaxy for
the glory of the Empire.
SPOCK (VO):
First officer's personal log.
Captain Kirk has annihilated
the Halkan people...
and I was unable to prevent it.
I find myself torn...
between loyalty to the Empire... and the
logic which predicts its inevitable demise.
Status report.
All torpedoes impacted, Captain.
The Halkan cities have been destroyed.
Thank you, Jones.
The name's Smith, sir.
Mr. Spock, would you mind
telling me what just happened?
Since when do you question
Imperial orders?
I merely pointed out the obvious advantages
of an alternate course of action.
Which you elected to ignore.
Uhura. Contact Starfleet.
Let them that we...
That I have completed the mission.
Notify them that strip-mining of the
planet's dilithium can proceed.
Also...
Make note of Mr. Spock's objection.
Aye, sir.
Ensign Chekov reporting for...
Captain. I wish to thank you for
permitting me to resume my duties.
- I trust you've learned your lesson, Ensign?
- Yes sir!
Good.
- Take him back to the agony booth.
- But, Captain...
- I changed my mind.
- But sir, you said...!
I changed my mind!
[CHEKOV SCREAMS]
Lieutenant. Have Mr. Leslie
report to the navigation station.
UHURA: Aye, sir.
SMITH: Captain...
I'm reading additional detonations
beneath the planet's crust.
What sort of detonations?
It looks like our torpedo barrage triggered
a reaction in the planet's dilithium strata.
The crystal lattices are
being destroyed.
Piezoelectric charges, Captain.
No doubt planted by the Halkans.
Kirk to transporter room.
Scotty. Beam as many dilithium crystals
as possible directly to the cargo bay.
Captain. With all those explosions
there's no way to get a lock.
Besides, the transporter circuits are...
I don't need excuses, Mr. Scott!
I need solutions!
Are you capable of
providing them?
I'll get right on it, sir.
The dilithium was rigged to explode.
Why didn't you detect that?
Captain. I advised against
this course of action.
The logical decision was...
You're not paid to lecture me
in logic, Mr. Spock!
You're paid to do your job!
I believe I am, sir.
I'll be in my quarters.
- Lieutenant.
- Uh-uh, Commander. Don't look at me.
The Captain's enemies aren't around
long. And I don't intend to be one of them.
Commander...
Three Andorian vessels dropping out of
warp just outside the system.
Computer.
Analysis of approaching ships.
COMPUTER (VO):
Working.
Kumari-class battle cruisers.
Armaments: 180-degree particle cannons.
Hull composition: duranium alloy.
Top of the line.
We're receiving a transmission
from the Andorians...
They say they witnessed the
destruction of the Halkans....
And they no longer recognize the
authority of the Terran Empire.
It has begun.
- What has?
- Revolution, Lieutenant.
Revolution.
What's wrong?
I'll tell you what's wrong...
What's wrong has pointed ears
and a knack for insubordination.
Spock's been the best first
officer I could ever hope for.
What's he playing at?
[INTERCOM WHISTLE]
SPOCK (VO):
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
Speak of the devil.
Captain here.
Captain.
Long range sensors detect Andorian
rebels on an intercept course.
If they make any aggressive moves,
destroy them. Kirk out.
Captain.
The Andorian government will not...
Once again offering your opinion
when none is requested!
Destroy them!
I will not.
All right, Spock.
You're angling for something.
What is it you want?
What did that imposter offer you?
What he offered me, Captain...
...is something you cannot give.
I was right.
The whole galaxy has gone crazy.
What happened while I was gone?
The imposter has obviously
been in my chair.
Where else has he been?
[COY LAUGHTER]
SPOCK:
The actions taken against the
Halkans have been illogical.
They shall likely serve as a catalyst...
Which may jeopardize the
Empire's very survival.
There is, however...
...a path to the future.
But that future may not involve
our present command.
Spock...
We had a good run, you and I.
[FIZZLES OUT]
No.
- No!
- James...
What's wrong with it?
Why isn't it working?
- I don't know.
- Why isn't it working?
Security detail to my quarters.
Belay that order.
Kirk to Farrell.
Farrell here, sir.
Send two of my personal guards to
my cabin. On the double.
On the double, sir.
And keep this channel secure.
Kirk out.
What are you gonna do?
Put an end to this insanity
once and for all.
Why?
Worried about me?
I am the Captain's woman.
You are.
Aren't you?
Always.
[DOOR BUZZES]
Come.
Captain.
Escort me to the bridge.
We're taking Commander
Spock into custody.
Sir?
Do you have a hearing
problem, mister?
No, sir.
Wait for me.
I'll be back in an hour.
Commander. What the Captain's
asking for... it's not possible!
Mr. Scott. I must speak with you.
Off the record.
Sir?
When you were in the
other reality...
What did you see?
I... erm...
I saw weakness, Commander.
Perhaps what you saw...
was peace.
Is that possible, Mr. Scott?
Commander, that kind of talk will
only lead to one place.
The agony booth!
You speak of weakness...
But the true weakness lies
within the Terran Empire.
It is held together by
tenuous bonds of fear.
The destruction of the
Halkan civilization...
...will serve as the final straw
for the outer colonies.
Insurrection was
inescapable.
But it has now
been accelerated.
We cannot survive a
full-scale rebellion.
But the peace that you
witnessed over there...
...is not impossible in our
reality as well.
Mr. Spock!
What you're saying... it's...
Mutiny.
KIRK (VO):
Captain's log, supplemental.
Something happened during
my time away from the Enterprise.
Commander Spock has become
emboldened to seek the Captain's chair.
But he's questioned my
orders for the final time.
Mr. Spock, you're
under arrest...
Where's my science officer?
I don't know sir, I...
Where's Mr. Spock?
I believe he's in the
transporter room, Captain.
Good girl.
Phasers at the ready.
I would not wanna be
Mr. Spock right now.
I'm not even sure I
wanna be on this ship.
Where's Mr. Spock?
- Captain...
- Where's Mr. Spock?
What did you witness, Crewman?
Let's try this again...
Mr. Spock is a traitor.
I wanna know where he is.
[ELECTRICAL CHARGE]
[SCREAMS]
Take him to Sickbay.
Let McCoy reason with him.
All hands, this is the Captain.
First Officer Spock has mutinied
and fled the bridge.
He is to be incapacitated
on sight and placed under arrest.
The crewman who accomplishes this
will be promoted two steps in grade.
Kirk out.
[PHASER FIRE]
I suggest you put down
your weapon, laddie.
[SCREAMS IN AGONY]
Doctor.
Another dose.
I've never used this
much before.
I wonder what'll happen.
[SCREAMS IN PAIN]
[HEARTBEAT INCREASES]
Captain.
He's of no value dead.
This isn't your day, is it?
Dr. McCoy is really
enjoying this.
Unless you want
him to continue...
Where's Mr. Spock?
He...
He was headed to auxiliary control.
With Mr. Scott.
- He's all yours, Doctor.
- Yes, sir.
And give that traitorous elf a slap
from me when you catch him, Jim.
Oh no... [SCREAMS]
Kirk to Sulu.
Security Chief Sulu, come in.
Sulu here.
Take a team to auxiliary control.
Apprehend Mr. Spock and
Lieutenant Commander Scott.
Lethal force is authorized.
Lethal force, Captain?
There'll likely be casualties
on both sides.
Then take Chekov and put him
in front. Kirk out.
I've gotta go.
Ohhh. Don't be such a
party pooper, Hikaru.
I'm serious.
It's not often the Captain gives anyone
a second chance. I intend to take it.
Besides... with Scott and
Spock outta the way...
Guess who's next in line
for first officer?
Of course...
And you'll give me that commendation?
I told you I would, didn't I?
- Same time next week?
- Always.
You know you're my favorite.
[McKENNAH SIGHS]
I've locked out bridge control.
Transferred navigation, helm, and
long range communications to us.
Seal off the armory.
Secure as many decks as possible.
Aye, sir.
Thank you,
Mr. Scott.
Broadcast this recording on
all ship channels.
Their phasers...
They're only set to stun!
Murder is the way of the Empire.
The way of the Captain.
A way that must change.
Join us, Mr. Chekov!
Be a part of the future!
Not of the past.
[RED ALERT KLAXON]
Status report.
The Andorian vessels have
entered orbit, sir.
They're charging weapons.
Sound general quarters.
Ready main phaser banks.
They're demanding we
surrender, Captain.
That was a warning shot
across our bow.
- Shields are holding.
- Warning shot? Cowards.
Lock onto their lead
ship and fire.
- Captain?
- I said "Fire"!
Aye, sir!
Weapons are locked out!
Locked out from where?
[BOSUN WHISTLE]
SPOCK (VO):
Attention crew of the
I.S.S. Enterprise.
This is First Officer Spock.
By now you are aware of the annihilation
of the peaceful Halkan people.
KIRK:
Lieutenant!
Kill that broadcast!
SPOCK (VO):
This action has served only to hasten
the fall of the Terran Empire.
A civilization built upon a legacy
of violence and terror cannot survive.
- Kill that broadcast!
- I can't, sir!
SPOCK (VO):
The time has come to
embrace a new vision.
A vision of equality.
Of morality.
Of galactic peace.
A philosophy based upon
infinite diversity...
...infinite combinations.
This future is within our reach.
But not under our
present command.
Join me.
Together we shall be the
architects of our own future.
KIRK (VO):
Captain's Log supplemental.
The Andorians are seeking
vengeance for the Halkans.
And First Officer Spock is a
traitor to me and the Empire.
I will not lose the Enterprise.
Our shields won't hold
forever, Commander.
Sir, she said she needed
to speak with you.
She poses no threat.
Commander. We need to get
to Captain Kirk's quarters. Quickly!
Lieutenant Moreau, it would
be extremely unwise to...
Dammit, Mr. Spock!
I can help.
Just come with me. Please!
Mr. Scott.
Encode a message
to the Andorians.
Inform them that we have
control of the Enterprise...
...and we are prepared to
join their cause.
I shall return momentarily.
Or you won't return at all.
[SPOCK'S RECORDING REPEATS]
Lieutenant!
Shut off that damn recording!
Sir, the Andorians are powering
down their weapons.
I'm detecting a transmission
from auxiliary control, Captain.
We're suing for peace.
The hell we are...!
Where's Mr. Leslie?
Mr. Leslie didn't report
for duty, sir.
Well get someone up
here to cover his shift!
I want a navigator!
I want one now!
So, this is it?!
This is what I've got to work with?!
I can navigate
the Enterprise, sir.
Whatever you want.
Set a course for Starbase 34.
Maximum warp.
I'm sorry, Captain! The controls
aren't responding! I tried! I can't!
You can't!
You say you can pilot my ship!
You can't even get us out of orbit!
Navigation has been rerouted
to auxiliary control.
There's nothing I can do.
Lieutenant.
You're relieved of your commission.
Report to the brig.
- Sir?
- Captain, it's not her fault!
I said report to the brig!
That's enough!
We found him unconscious
on Deck 8, sir.
Chekov and the other men...
They've turned.
Resume your post.
Am I not merciful?
Sulu.
You've got the conn.
I want control of my ship!
Or it's the booth for the lot of you!
What are you looking at?
You heard the Captain.
Get to work.
I was hoping you'd come
back during my shift.
Oh.
You happy to see me?
Always.
The device of which the other
Captain spoke, I presume.
I am surprised Captain Kirk
did not use it on me.
Oh.
He tried.
Fascinating.
James met an alien scientist...
...at the Starfleet penal colony
on Tantalus Five.
He pillaged her laboratory
after he dispensed with her.
Then he stole this device.
One touch and your problems
are over, Mr. Spock.
This'll change everything.
You would see me use
this device on him?
I would.
But you...
...are the Captain's woman.
Yes.
But not this Captain.
No revolution can succeed using the same
methods which failed in the previous one.
Commander...
Spock...
Please find a way.
A way to send me where he went.
I cannot.
Please!
It is not within my power.
But you can make
a difference here.
All clear, sir.
Wait outside.
Captain Kirk to Mr. Spock.
Spock here.
Commander.
There's no reason we can't talk
about this like civilized men.
I've listened to your logic
and I find it compelling.
There's merit in what
you say, Spock.
I see the potential for change.
The opportunity to better
the Empire.
Spock...
I have the bridge.
You have auxiliary control.
Who makes the next move?
What do you propose?
We meet...
Somewhere neutral...
Half an hour.
Deck Five.
Officer's Lounge.
No weapons.
No tricks.
Just you and I.
We've had many successes together, Spock.
I know we can work this out.
Very well.
Half an hour.
You don't actually
trust him, do you?
Of course not.
It's some kind of set-up!
Why play his game?
If there is any hope for
the Empire to change...
I must give Captain Kirk the
opportunity to do so as well.
Captain...
Commander...
No weapons.
I've considered our game
while you were away.
Bishop to Queen's level two.
Knight takes Bishop.
You've left your King vulnerable.
As have you.
Seems we're at a stalemate.
Spock...
You can't win.
What's your next move?
Kill me? Take command of the Enterprise?
There are a dozen starships out
there. All loyal to the Empire.
As am I.
But the Empire as it stands
today is at a crossroads.
Eventually all Kings are vulnerable.
He put these thoughts into that Vulcan
head of yours, didn't he? That...
That other captain.
Spock...
After all we've been through.
All we've accomplished.
Earned for ourselves!
You would trust a stranger
from another universe?
I believe I would.
That Captain had a vision of an
imminent future which you fail to see.
Then you're an even bigger
fool than I imagined.
Your mutiny ends.
Right here and now.
You didn't really think I'd let you
walk out of here did you?
And now it comes to this.
Checkmate.
Perhaps not.
Mr. Scott implemented a level three
energy dampening field on this deck.
Yet another act of treachery...
which proves, once again...
...why your command must
come to an end.
Report!
The tectonic explosions are
destabilizing the planet's orbit!
We've run simulations of dilithium
generator strata in the chem lab.
I've seen this sort
of thing before!
The Andorian ships have broken
orbit and gone to warp, sir!
They've got the right idea, lad!
Put some distance between
us and that planet!
There's that human side!
I always knew you'd kill me
to get the Captain's chair!
You're no better than
the rest of us...!
[KIRK GASPS FOR AIR]
Captain Kirk.
The future is coming.
You are the past.
I offer this crew an alternative.
This crew...
This crew?
They don't need alternatives.
They're pawns.
Pawns need a King!
They serve for my conquests.
My victories!
You think they're smart
enough to follow you?
They're mine!
I can use them!
Break them!
Send them to their own slaughter!
And they'll thank me for it!
[KIRK'S SPEECH ECHOES SHIPWIDE]
You double crossing
half-breed traitor!
James T. Kirk.
You are hereby relieved of command.
Let go of me!
Do you realize
what you're doing?!
I do.
KIRK:
You're a coward, Spock.
You don't even have the guts
to execute us like a real leader.
This shuttlecraft is at
your disposal.
I recommend setting a course
to the nearest habitable system.
You have sufficient supplies
to last until then.
You think that changes anything?
So you've taken control of one ship.
So what? What now?
Peace?
Freedom?
The Empire will hunt you down
like the mangy dog that you are.
Perhaps...
But I must try...
You won't get away
with this, Spock.
You're just one man.
In every revolution there is
one man with a vision.
Who told you that?
You did.
Spock...!!!
[KIRK'S CRY CONTINUES TO ECHO]
Commander.
Status report.
All decks reporting in, Captain.
The Halkan survivors are safely on board.
Shuttlecraft Galileo is
leaving sensor range.
James T. Kirk chose his path.
It is time we chose ours.
Warp two, Ensign.
Heading, sir?
Forward.
English Subtitles by:
Peter Goundrill