POWER SOURCE
Captain’s log.
Stardate 6050.5
The Farragut has been ordered to the Chorus system
to locate the USS Azrael,
under the command of Captain Arron Glenn.
The Azrael was investigating the recent
discovery of some unusual alien technology,
deep in uncharted space.
Just three days into our mission,
all communications with the Azrael ceased.
It is our mission to uncover the reason
for the communication disruption,
and to offer any assistance
that may be required.
Captain, I have a ship on intercept course,
approaching at warp 6.
Identification!
A Federation starship.
NCC-517
It’s the USS Azrael, sir.
She’s dropping out of warp.
Helm, disengage warp engines.
Hi, sir.
Cutting into impulse engines.
Hailing frequencies.
This is Captain John T. Carter,
of the starship Farragut.
Acknowledge.
Status on that ship, RT.
Nothing unusual.
No malfunctions.
Lifesigns normal.
Captain Glenn,
This is Captain John T. Carter
of the starship Farragut.
Report your status!
Do you require assistance?
Captain, the Azrael is firing photon torpedoes.
She’s making a room for it, sir.
Heading 3-60 mark zero. Warp factor 6.
Lay down pursuit course, Mr. Taylor.
Match her speed!
Hi, sir!
Pursuit course laid in.
Engage!
The engines!
They’re not responding!
- Engineering!
- Smithfield here.
Damage report, Mike.
Who ever that was,
they knew exactly where to hit us.
That attack took our  warp systems.
How bad is it?
They did a nifty job of crippling us for the short term.
But nothing major.
I should be able to get us back online
in a few hours.
That was the Azrael that fired on us,
and I need to find out why!
Any chance of a... previse repair estimate?
I can cut that time in half,
provided that you stay away
from my engine room.
You’ve got a deal.
Doctor Holley,
report to the briefing room.
RT, Mr. Prescott, you with me.
Mr. Taylor, you have the conn.
Just 3 days in the Azrael’s mission,
and all communications went dark.
Her coming out to meet us in deep space
means that she’s been receiving
Starfleet communications all along.
They knew we were coming,
and hitted us off before
we can reach the Chorus system.
A premeditated assault on another Federation vessel
Does it make sense?
Glenn’s service record is flawless
He’s a man at unswerving character.
You’ve worked with captain Glenn
before, Mr Prescott?
A training mission, sir.
Starfleet Academy.
Very good!
Starfleet has given us
roll at logs and data
from the Azrael’s 3 day mission
for other analysis.
My initial impression is that he may
not be responsible for his actions.
Watch closely.
I want everyone’s input.
Captain’s log,
Stardate 6047.2
The strange energy emanating from the fifth planet in the system
has led us to an incredible discovery
advanced alien devices in orbit of the gas giant
seem to be joining gases from the atmosphere.
This massive, spherical construction
appear to be using the gases as some form of fuel.
Preliminary scans indicate that these devices
are generating the strange energy emissions
permeating the system.
Captain’s log.
Stardate 6048.4
My analysis of the... uh...
...alien devices surrounding Chorus 5
is producing some...
...interesting results.
More and more I’m starting to see
the relationship between...
...the machines in orbit and the... uh...
...gases in the atmosphere.
If I can just gain...
...access to the internal systems...
...of these machines...
...I am certain that I would
be able to unlock their secret.
I will continue to...
...collect the data...
...and work too hard
in high policies.
Our mission to Chorus 5
...has shielded phenomenal results.
I’ve learned more then I could have hoped for.
Everything is becoming clear!
I realize my purpose, now.
and I intend to see this experiment through
to the ultimate conclusion!
Nothing shall stand in my way! Nothing!
That’s the last log entry.
Thoughts?
There was a clear change of personality,
if I ever saw one.
From increasing signs of stress and fatigue
to an obsessive nature.
Did you noticed his eyes...
...an almost red as glow.
No tell in what’s affecting him.
What state of mind he’s in?
Or the rest of his crew!
No one on that ship has made any attempt
to get a message to the Starfleet.
And they’ve had plenty of opportunity.
His attack on Farragut was deliberately
designed to put us out of commission,
but not to destroy us.
He want’s to delay us, and that’s all.
- For what purpose?
- That alien technology.
It looks like he was on to something.
Maybe he just want
to buy a little more time.
Why the strange behavior?
The sudden obsession?
The abrupt disinterest on logging his progress?
Could there be an alien force at work here?
You mean something we haven’t seen on these logs?
Well, I think he’d be giving something away
if he made contact with an alien presence.
I’m more inclined to believe
that those unusual energy vestige
may be responsible for his condition.
Which could put Farragut at risk
as soon as we get on range.
I want you to examine these logs
and associated data in more detail.
See what you income out with before we get under way.
Mr. Prescott,
Brief your men on the situation
and prepare them for
potential hostile encounter.
We may need to beam aboard
the Azrael and take it by force.
Very well, sir.
Doctor,
You can assist Comander Tacket
by analyzing that energy.
Find out if we’re at risk,
and what you can do
to conter-act it’s effect.
Hi, sir.
Dismissed.
Remember that we are dealing
with another starfleet ship and crew.
The attack on the Farragut
disabled our warp system only.
No other damage was inflicted.
As far as the crew as concern we can’t assume anything.
Whatever is driving their actions
cannot as yet be determined.
But it appears to be causing
a progressive change.
I’m counting on each of you to hold your emotions in check,
and to fight any strange urge that you may experience.
The captain may be setting us in to take control of the Azrael.
In the mean time we remain
on red alert readiness.
Dismissed!
It was an honor to serve
under you, Captain Glenn.
I’ll never forget that
first training mission.
I learned a lot from you.
I was looking forward to seen you again and
reverencing all my time at the Academy.
- How you’re coming, Mr. Galway?
- Almost there, sir.
Just... one... more...
Ouch!
Are you OK?
Fine, sir.
just a lapse in concentration.
When I get a hold on that Captain Glenn,
he’s gonna be answering to me personally.
For damage to the warp drive?
Or myself electrocution?
Both!
I believe that does it.
And at record time!
Engineering to bridge.
- Bridge here.
- We’re back online, captain.
Full warp capability as in your command.
Thanks, Mike!
Mr. Taylor, lay in a course to
the Chorus system. Warp factor 6.
- Course laid in, sir.
- Engage.
Captain’s Log, stardate: 6050.8.
En route to the Quorus system,
we were intercepted by the Azrael
and fired upon unexpectedly.
The attack was specifically designed
to knock out our warp systems,
which we believe was intended to
delay our reaching the fifth planet.
After relatively quick repairs,
we resumed our original course and
now have arrived at Quorus Five.
The Azrael is holding its
position near the gas giant
and has not made a
move since our arrival.
Magnify.
Amazing!
Fascinating!
Analysis, RT.
Those devices seem to be using the
entire planet as a source of fuel
to create a strange type of
energy that I can’t identify.
Some residual energy is escaping
the planet’s gravitational pull
and penetrating both
Azrael and Farragut.
Our shields?
They appear to have no effect
on repelling the energy.
What is your threat assessment?
Unknown. This is unlike
anything I’ve seen before.
Our sensors aren’t
picking up anything new
that we haven’t been able to analyze
from top to bottom
from the Azrael feeds.
I was afraid of that.
Hail the Azrael. Let’s
see if they’ll talk.
Farragut to Azrael, do you read?
Sir, I’m getting something...
I mean someone, but...
What is it?
This... person is ordering us
to leave the system immediately.
Put me on.
Azrael, this is Captain John
T. Carter of the USS Farragut.
What’s your situation?
*This is Commodore Sheila
Johnson of the USS Azrael.*
*As I outrank you and, quite frankly,
can outthink and outfight you,*
*I hereby order you to
hightail it out of this system*
*before I take measures
to destroy your ship!*
Commodore who?
Look, I don’t care who
the hell you think you are,
put me through to
Captain Glenn immediately!
*You have ten minutes to comply
with my order! Azrael out!*
I might be mistaken, but
I don’t recall mention of
a Commodore Johnson
serving on the Azrael.
No, sir. However, there
is an Ensign Sheila Johnson
serving as the ship’s Comm Officer.
Ensign?
Captain, the Azrael’s shields are down.
Very odd for a ship
planning to attack us.
Any chance you can pinpoint
Captain Glenn’s location?
I could if we had access
to Glenn’s medical records.
A narrow band sensor array is capable
of picking up a unique bio signature.
Those records would be available
in the Azrael’s databanks.
I should be able to access them
with command level override codes.
If they haven’t locked out access.
Let’s give it a try.
*Access granted.*
Computer, download medical
records for Captain Aaron Glenn
and tie into the ship’s sensor array.
*Working.*
*Task complete.*
She’s all yours, RT.
Got him. He’s in the
Science Lab on deck five.
Mike, report to the bridge.
We’re beaming over to the Azrael.
You’re in command.
Mr. Prescott, meet us in the
transporter room with one of your staff.
Does it seem excessively
hot in here to you, Captain?
It must be over forty
degrees Celsius in here.
Intruders!
Get them!
Phasers on stun.
Call security!
No affect. Heavy stun.
Did you see their eyes?
It’s a good chance that
the energy from Quorus Five
is causing the abnormal
behaviors and appearances.
And it’s going to
begin affecting us soon.
Right, no time to waste.
Let’s get to Glenn and get some answers.
Commander, we’re receiving
another communication
from the alleged “Commodore”
Johnson. Should I respond?
No. Maintain communication
silence for the moment
while Jack and his team are on board.
Mr. Thelin, is there any
change in the Azrael’s status?
No, sir. It’s... wait a second.
That’s odd.
What is it?
I don’t quite know. My
instruments seem to be acting up.
I’m reading wild
fluctuations in our position.
One second it’s showing
where we’re supposed to be
and the next it has us
somewhere else completely.
It’s not just you.
I’m seeing some strange
anomalies here as well.
Every time I try to correct
it, it just goes off again.
Smithfield to Galway.
*Galway here.*
What’s going on down there?
We’re experiencing some
instrumentation failures.
I’m registering multiple
failures in most of
the primary, secondary,
and tertiary systems.
But it’s sporadic...
It’s jumping around.
*Run diagnostics on all systems.*
*I want to know why my ship is acting up!*
Diagnostics aren’t working
either. I need your help fast
or we’re going to lose
environmental systems too!
On my way.
Mr. Thelin, you have the con.
Whoa! What just caused that?
I can’t nail it down.
Every time I try to
compensate for one system,
another one goes down.
This is getting us nowhere.
Agreed.
Let’s shut down all systems and
bring them back up under manual control.
We’ll route minimal power to
non-critical systems and lock
them down on a fixed setting.
Alright. Let’s do it.
That seems to have done
the trick... For the moment.
Congratulations, Chief.
Thanks.
Don’t get too comfortable though.
I want you to monitor
these systems constantly.
Advise me of anything
unusual. I’ll be on the bridge.
Aye, sir.
Why can’t I solve this? It’s all here...
I have all I need... I
must solve it... I must...
Captain Glenn?
And you are...?
Carter, Sir. Captain John T.
Carter of the USS Farragut.
I don’t remember inviting you!
Do you want to explain to
me why you fired on my ship?
Nonsense. I didn’t fire on anyone!
And I strongly suggest
that you leave my ship
before I’m forced to
deal with you personally!
What’s the big experiment,
Glenn? What are you doing here?
You wouldn’t understand!
RT?
He is tapped into those
devices orbiting Quorus Five.
They appear to be part of a network
of machines all working in concert.
But for what purpose, I can’t say.
Alright, that’s it Glenn.
You will relinquish
command to my Security Chief
and accompany me
peacefully to the Farragut.
The Azrael will then
follow us out of the system.
Go away!
I have important research
and I cannot be disturbed!
Let me try, sir.
Captain Glenn, it’s me, Henry Prescott.
Starfleet Academy training
mission to Altair Six?
You were my commanding
officer on that mission...
My only mission is
to solve this mystery!
And I don’t care who you are!
Mr. Prescott, Captain
Glenn is under arrest.
Take him into custody, please.
Aye, sir.
Captain Glenn, please come with me.
I... am not going anywhere.
Sorry, Mr. Prescott. I know it
must have been difficult to see
your former commanding officer
behaving behaving like that.
Yes, sir, it was.
Let’s get him back to the Farragut
and see if we can sort this out.
Where are you taking us?
To the brig, of course.
Now, Mr. Prescott!
Good aim, Commander.
Just because I’m a man of science
doesn’t mean I can’t handle a phaser.
Thanks, RT.
Carter here.
Just checking in, Jack.
Is everything alright over there?
It is now. We had a bit of an incident,
but everything’s under control.
Tell Doc Holley to stand by
to receive 3 priority patients.
Sir, Captain Glenn is gone.
He must have slipped away
while we were dealing with these guards.
Correction, prepare for
two priority patients.
We’ll be back momentarily. Carter out.
Any thoughts, RT?
It’s your hand, Jack. How
do you want to play it?
I’m more worried about what
Glenn has up his sleeve.
We don’t have time to track him down.
I’ll need you to start analyzing
Glenn’s data on those machines.
Judging by what we’ve seen already,
there isn’t much time.
I’m on it.
Mr. Prescott. I have a
feeling we’re going to need you
to execute that hostile
takeover plan we discussed.
Let’s go check on
your guard and get back
to the Farragut so you
can prepare your team.
Very well, sir!
Is it cold in here to you?
It does seem like they’ve
turned the heat down a bit.
Computer, increase the
temperature by ten degrees.
Why do you think these
guards were acting so bizarre?
That’s what I’m trying
to find out, Ensign.
Now if you’re through asking questions,
maybe you can assist me with
the analysis of this data.
Maybe I don’t want to help.
I was supposed to be
taking the day off anyway.
Are you refusing a direct
order from your superior?
What order? You said
“maybe” I could help you.
Well, “maybe” I don’t want to.
That’s true, you didn’t
actually order him.
I don’t think I’m going
to assist you anymore!
You can work out this
problem by yourself!
- What?!
- You heard me!
Ensign, you are relieved of
duty and confined to quarters!
Fine! See if you can do this without me!
What have you got, RT?
From the tone of your
message, it must be pretty big.
You bet it is, Jack.
Let’s have it.
Well, we’ve been correct
all along about one thing.
Those devices are drawing
the gases from the atmosphere
and using it as some sort of fuel.
The entire planet is
basically being turned
into a gigantic power source.
What in heaven’s name would anyone
need with such a huge power source?
My analysis concludes
multiple possibilities.
Things I never dreamed possible.
Things that could change Starfleet
and the human race forever.
I don’t follow.
There’s more. Captain Glenn
has successfully established
a remote connection to the
power generating mechanism.
And he’s attempting to activate it.
Can he do that? Does
he have the knowledge?
Not in his state of mind.
Well, I suppose there’s
a remote chance of
him hitting the right
combination, but not likely.
But if he tries?
The results could be
disastrous for everything
within a parsec of this system.
That’s all I need to know.
It’s imperative that we get both ships
as far away from this
planet as soon as possible.
- No!
- No?
We can’t leave yet.
Explain.
Maybe Glenn can’t activate
the device properly,
but I know I can. I must.
The scientific knowledge that
could be gained is enormous!
We can’t risk it.
I’m not going to abandon
this opportunity, Jack.
This is what I was meant for.
This is the reason I went into
sciences in the first place.
I have to see this through!
We’re going to take over the Azrael
and both ships are leaving
the system as soon as possible.
This experiment is concluded.
That’s an order, Mr. Tacket!
Noooo! I won’t let you!
Listen to yourself! Look at yourself!
This isn’t you, RT! Snap out of it!
Iím sorry. I donít
know what got into me.
It was like I wasn’t in control.
It’s that damned planet!
We’re getting out of here... right now.
Carter to Prescott.
*Prescott here.*
Have your security team
in the transporter room
on the double, armed and ready!
Transporter room, prepare
to beam security detail
to the Azrael bridge on my command.
Is it cold in here or what?
Sir, the Azrael has
raised their shields.
Confirmed. Looks like
Glenn still has some sense
of what’s going on around him.
Lt. Taylor, where are you going?
I’m taking a break.
Time for a swift cuppa
and a spot of lunch.
What’s it to you?!
Return to your station
immediately, mister!
I’m sorry, sir. I really
don’t know what came over me.
Mr. Thelin, I want a
precision attack on the Azrael.
Minimum force necessary to
bring down their shields.
As soon as they’re down,
cease fire immediately.
Maneuvering thrusters only.
Coming into position now, sir.
Evasive!
I can’t do it, sir. It’s too difficult.
Focus, Thelin! Stay on him!
Jack, I’m reading a build-up
of energy from the planet!
I’m aware of that, Robert!
Can someone turn up the damn heat
in here so I can concentrate?!
The Azrael shields are down!
Transporter room! Now!
The Azrael... it’s firing phasers
and photon torpedoes again!
Shields are at sixty percent!
Continue evasive maneuvers,
but don’t return fire!
Just keep us safe for
a few moments longer!
What are you doing here?!
Jones, take these
trespassers to the brig!
The Azrael has disarmed.
Carter to Prescott.
*Prescott here.*
I assume that the Azrael’s
crew was less than cooperative?
On the contrary, sir,
they were very cooperative.
*Well, don’t just stand there.*
*Get that ship moving and
follow us out of the system.*
Aye, sir.
Energy build-up is almost complete!
Get us out of here! Warp factor six!
Captain’s log, supplemental.
After surviving the massive
planetary explosion of Quorus Five,
Captain Glenn is making
preparations to depart.
His mission is to resume exploration
of the remnants of that system.
Starfleet hopes that
they will uncover answers
to some very disconcerting questions.
Thanks once again for pulling
us out of the jam back there.
I feel pretty foolish.
I almost led us all to our destruction
over a petty obsession.
Doctor Holley is sure
that you and your crew
were not responsible for your actions.
And yet she couldn’t produce evidence
of any medical reason for our condition.
We all suffered something from being
exposed to that alien technology.
You, Mr. Prescott? I
don’t recall noticing
you having any difficulties.
My particular training should have
allowed me to keep it under control.
However, my performance in the lab
would seem to indicate otherwise.
Well, in the end you
came through for us.
Yes. Captain Glenn, I’m... sorry
for what happened on the Azrael bridge.
I hope you don’t think less of me.
On the contrary. You’ve
once again demonstrated
excellence in the
performance of your duty.
Anyway, the whole thing seems
somehow unreal now.
Thank you, sir.
I’m just sorry your
Smithfield couldn’t be here.
I was rather looking
forward to meeting her.
No, sir, you might
not enjoy that meeting.
She’s still in her engine
room trying to repair
the mess that she thinks you caused.
The last time I saw
her she was grumbling
something that included
your name and some
choice words that I had to look up.
Come.
Don’t tell me you forgot about
our Friday night poker game.
Well, to tell you the truth...
He did.
I know that look.
You’ve got something on your mind.
Don’t we all?
We were witness to an amazing display
of power and an
incredible feat of genius.
I can’t help but wonder if there are
more remnants of that
unusual alien technology.
My money says there is,
but what I’m more curious about
is what that technology was used for.
When you were insisting
that we activate the device
you seemed pretty close
to some sort of revelation.
It’s like a dream now.
You know how the most ridiculous things
can seem logical when
you’re having a dream,
but when you wake up you
can’t make sense of it
no matter how hard you try?
The way my engineering
systems kept acting up...
that certainly feels more
like a dream now than reality.
At least I wish it was a dream.
Well, Prescott thinks it was meant
to be some sort of doomsday weapon.
I’d rather think that it
had a more positive use.
Quorus Four is a good
orbital distance from the sun
and with a little help
could be terraformed
into a nice little habitable planet.
All it would need is a
good secondary energy source
to maintain an ideal
Class M environment.
A logical possibility
if a bit unromantic.
I can imagine that power being used
to fuel perhaps a massive
teleportation device...
one that could send entire civilizations
to the other side of the known universe.
Talk about the ultimate
mission of first contact...
Translation, proofreading,
subtitling and synchronization:
BrThing, Mark Hildebrand and other