Captain’s log, supplemental.
After surviving the massive
planetary explosion of Quorus Five,
Captain Glenn is making
preparations to depart.
His mission is to resume exploration
of the remnants of that system.
Starfleet hopes that
they will uncover answers
to some very disconcerting questions.
Thanks once again for pulling
us out of the jam back there.
I feel pretty foolish.
I almost led us all to our destruction
over a petty obsession.
Doctor Holley is sure
that you and your crew
were not responsible for your actions.
And yet she couldn’t produce evidence
of any medical reason for our condition.
We all suffered something from being
exposed to that alien technology.
You, Mr. Prescott? I
don’t recall noticing
you having any difficulties.
My particular training should have
allowed me to keep it under control.
However, my performance in the lab
would seem to indicate otherwise.
Well, in the end you
came through for us.
Yes. Captain Glenn, I’m... sorry
for what happened on the Azrael bridge.
I hope you don’t think less of me.
On the contrary. You’ve
once again demonstrated
excellence in the
performance of your duty.
Anyway, the whole thing seems
somehow unreal now.
Thank you, sir.
I’m just sorry your
Smithfield couldn’t be here.
I was rather looking
forward to meeting her.
No, sir, you might
not enjoy that meeting.
She’s still in her engine
room trying to repair
the mess that she thinks you caused.
The last time I saw
her she was grumbling
something that included
your name and some
choice words that I had to look up.
Come.
Don’t tell me you forgot about
our Friday night poker game.
Well, to tell you the truth...
He did.
I know that look.
You’ve got something on your mind.
Don’t we all?
We were witness to an amazing display
of power and an
incredible feat of genius.
I can’t help but wonder if there are
more remnants of that
unusual alien technology.
My money says there is,
but what I’m more curious about
is what that technology was used for.
When you were insisting
that we activate the device
you seemed pretty close
to some sort of revelation.
It’s like a dream now.
You know how the most ridiculous things
can seem logical when
you’re having a dream,
but when you wake up you
can’t make sense of it
no matter how hard you try?
The way my engineering
systems kept acting up...
that certainly feels more
like a dream now than reality.
At least I wish it was a dream.
Well, Prescott thinks it was meant
to be some sort of doomsday weapon.
I’d rather think that it
had a more positive use.
Quorus Four is a good
orbital distance from the sun
and with a little help
could be terraformed
into a nice little habitable planet.
All it would need is a
good secondary energy source
to maintain an ideal
Class M environment.
A logical possibility
if a bit unromantic.
I can imagine that power being used
to fuel perhaps a massive
teleportation device...
one that could send entire civilizations
to the other side of the known universe.
Talk about the ultimate
mission of first contact...