POWER SOURCE
Captain’s log.
Stardate 6050.5
The Farragut has been ordered to the Chorus system
to locate the USS Azrael,
under the command of Captain Arron Glenn.
The Azrael was investigating the recent
discovery of some unusual alien technology,
deep in uncharted space.
Just three days into our mission,
all communications with the Azrael ceased.
It is our mission to uncover the reason
for the communication disruption,
and to offer any assistance
that may be required.
Captain, I have a ship on intercept course,
approaching at warp 6.
Identification!
A Federation starship.
NCC-517
It’s the USS Azrael, sir.
She’s dropping out of warp.
Helm, disengage warp engines.
Hi, sir.
Cutting into impulse engines.
Hailing frequencies.
This is Captain John T. Carter,
of the starship Farragut.
Acknowledge.
Status on that ship, RT.
Nothing unusual.
No malfunctions.
Lifesigns normal.
Captain Glenn,
This is Captain John T. Carter
of the starship Farragut.
Report your status!
Do you require assistance?
Captain, the Azrael is firing photon torpedoes.
She’s making a room for it, sir.
Heading 3-60 mark zero. Warp factor 6.
Lay down pursuit course, Mr. Taylor.
Match her speed!
Hi, sir!
Pursuit course laid in.
Engage!
The engines!
They’re not responding!
- Engineering!
- Smithfield here.
Damage report, Mike.
Who ever that was,
they knew exactly where to hit us.
That attack took our  warp systems.
How bad is it?
They did a nifty job of crippling us for the short term.
But nothing major.
I should be able to get us back online
in a few hours.
That was the Azrael that fired on us,
and I need to find out why!
Any chance of a... previse repair estimate?
I can cut that time in half,
provided that you stay away
from my engine room.
You’ve got a deal.
Doctor Holley,
report to the briefing room.
RT, Mr. Prescott, you with me.
Mr. Taylor, you have the conn.
Just 3 days in the Azrael’s mission,
and all communications went dark.
Her coming out to meet us in deep space
means that she’s been receiving
Starfleet communications all along.
They knew we were coming,
and hitted us off before
we can reach the Chorus system.
A premeditated assault on another Federation vessel
Does it make sense?
Glenn’s service record is flawless
He’s a man at unswerving character.
You’ve worked with captain Glenn
before, Mr Prescott?
A training mission, sir.
Starfleet Academy.
Very good!
Starfleet has given us
roll at logs and data
from the Azrael’s 3 day mission
for other analysis.
My initial impression is that he may
not be responsible for his actions.
Watch closely.
I want everyone’s input.
Captain’s log,
Stardate 6047.2
The strange energy emanating from the fifth planet in the system
has led us to an incredible discovery
advanced alien devices in orbit of the gas giant
seem to be joining gases from the atmosphere.
This massive, spherical construction
appear to be using the gases as some form of fuel.
Preliminary scans indicate that these devices
are generating the strange energy emissions
permeating the system.
Captain’s log.
Stardate 6048.4
My analysis of the... uh...
...alien devices surrounding Chorus 5
is producing some...
...interesting results.
More and more I’m starting to see
the relationship between...
...the machines in orbit and the... uh...
...gases in the atmosphere.
If I can just gain...
...access to the internal systems...
...of these machines...
...I am certain that I would
be able to unlock their secret.
I will continue to...
...collect the data...
...and work too hard
in high policies.
Our mission to Chorus 5
...has shielded phenomenal results.
I’ve learned more then I could have hoped for.
Everything is becoming clear!
I realize my purpose, now.
and I intend to see this experiment through
to the ultimate conclusion!
Nothing shall stand in my way! Nothing!
That’s the last log entry.
Thoughts?
There was a clear change of personality,
if I ever saw one.
From increasing signs of stress and fatigue
to an obsessive nature.
Did you noticed his eyes...
...an almost red as glow.
No tell in what’s affecting him.
What state of mind he’s in?
Or the rest of his crew!
No one on that ship has made any attempt
to get a message to the Starfleet.
And they’ve had plenty of opportunity.
His attack on Farragut was deliberately
designed to put us out of commission,
but not to destroy us.
He want’s to delay us, and that’s all.
- For what purpose?
- That alien technology.
It looks like he was on to something.
Maybe he just want
to buy a little more time.
Why the strange behavior?
The sudden obsession?
The abrupt disinterest on logging his progress?
Could there be an alien force at work here?
You mean something we haven’t seen on these logs?
Well, I think he’d be giving something away
if he made contact with an alien presence.
I’m more inclined to believe
that those unusual energy vestige
may be responsible for his condition.
Which could put Farragut at risk
as soon as we get on range.
I want you to examine these logs
and associated data in more detail.
See what you income out with before we get under way.
Mr. Prescott,
Brief your men on the situation
and prepare them for
potential hostile encounter.
We may need to beam aboard
the Azrael and take it by force.
Very well, sir.
Doctor,
You can assist Comander Tacket
by analyzing that energy.
Find out if we’re at risk,
and what you can do
to conter-act it’s effect.
Hi, sir.
Dismissed.
Remember that we are dealing
with another starfleet ship and crew.
The attack on the Farragut
disabled our warp system only.
No other damage was inflicted.
As far as the crew as concern we can’t assume anything.
Whatever is driving their actions
cannot as yet be determined.
But it appears to be causing
a progressive change.
I’m counting on each of you to hold your emotions in check,
and to fight any strange urge that you may experience.
The captain may be setting us in to take control of the Azrael.
In the mean time we remain
on red alert readiness.
Dismissed!
It was an honor to serve
under you, Captain Glenn.
I’ll never forget that
first training mission.
I learned a lot from you.
I was looking forward to seen you again and
reverencing all my time at the Academy.
- How you’re coming, Mr. Galway?
- Almost there, sir.
Just... one... more...
Ouch!
Are you OK?
Fine, sir.
just a lapse in concentration.
When I get a hold on that Captain Glenn,
he’s gonna be answering to me personally.
For damage to the warp drive?
Or myself electrocution?
Both!
I believe that does it.
And at record time!
Engineering to bridge.
- Bridge here.
- We’re back online, captain.
Full warp capability as in your command.
Thanks, Mike!
Mr. Taylor, lay in a course to
the Chorus system. Warp factor 6.
- Course laid in, sir.
- Engage.
Subtitle by BrThing