Captain’s Log, stardate: 6050.8.
En route to the Quorus system,
we were intercepted by the Azrael
and fired upon unexpectedly.
The attack was specifically designed
to knock out our warp systems,
which we believe was intended to
delay our reaching the fifth planet.
After relatively quick repairs,
we resumed our original course and
now have arrived at Quorus Five.
The Azrael is holding its
position near the gas giant
and has not made a
move since our arrival.
Magnify.
Amazing!
Fascinating!
Analysis, RT.
Those devices seem to be using the
entire planet as a source of fuel
to create a strange type of
energy that I can’t identify.
Some residual energy is escaping
the planet’s gravitational pull
and penetrating both
Azrael and Farragut.
Our shields?
They appear to have no effect
on repelling the energy.
What is your threat assessment?
Unknown. This is unlike
anything I’ve seen before.
Our sensors aren’t
picking up anything new
that we haven’t been able to analyze
from top to bottom
from the Azrael feeds.
I was afraid of that.
Hail the Azrael. Let’s
see if they’ll talk.
Farragut to Azrael, do you read?
Sir, I’m getting something...
I mean someone, but...
What is it?
This... person is ordering us
to leave the system immediately.
Put me on.
Azrael, this is Captain John
T. Carter of the USS Farragut.
What’s your situation?
*This is Commodore Sheila
Johnson of the USS Azrael.*
*As I outrank you and, quite frankly,
can outthink and outfight you,*
*I hereby order you to
hightail it out of this system*
*before I take measures
to destroy your ship!*
Commodore who?
Look, I don’t care who
the hell you think you are,
put me through to
Captain Glenn immediately!
*You have ten minutes to comply
with my order! Azrael out!*
I might be mistaken, but
I don’t recall mention of
a Commodore Johnson
serving on the Azrael.
No, sir. However, there
is an Ensign Sheila Johnson
serving as the ship’s Comm Officer.
Ensign?
Captain, the Azrael’s shields are down.
Very odd for a ship
planning to attack us.
Any chance you can pinpoint
Captain Glenn’s location?
I could if we had access
to Glenn’s medical records.
A narrow band sensor array is capable
of picking up a unique bio signature.
Those records would be available
in the Azrael’s databanks.
I should be able to access them
with command level override codes.
If they haven’t locked out access.
Let’s give it a try.
*Access granted.*
Computer, download medical
records for Captain Aaron Glenn
and tie into the ship’s sensor array.
*Working.*
*Task complete.*
She’s all yours, RT.
Got him. He’s in the
Science Lab on deck five.
Mike, report to the bridge.
We’re beaming over to the Azrael.
You’re in command.
Mr. Prescott, meet us in the
transporter room with one of your staff.
Does it seem excessively
hot in here to you, Captain?
It must be over forty
degrees Celsius in here.
Intruders!
Get them!
Phasers on stun.
Call security!
No affect. Heavy stun.
Did you see their eyes?
It’s a good chance that
the energy from Quorus Five
is causing the abnormal
behaviors and appearances.
And it’s going to
begin affecting us soon.
Right, no time to waste.
Let’s get to Glenn and get some answers.
Commander, we’re receiving
another communication
from the alleged “Commodore”
Johnson. Should I respond?
No. Maintain communication
silence for the moment
while Jack and his team are on board.
Mr. Thelin, is there any
change in the Azrael’s status?
No, sir. It’s... wait a second.
That’s odd.
What is it?
I don’t quite know. My
instruments seem to be acting up.
I’m reading wild
fluctuations in our position.
One second it’s showing
where we’re supposed to be
and the next it has us
somewhere else completely.
It’s not just you.
I’m seeing some strange
anomalies here as well.
Every time I try to correct
it, it just goes off again.
Smithfield to Galway.
*Galway here.*
What’s going on down there?
We’re experiencing some
instrumentation failures.
I’m registering multiple
failures in most of
the primary, secondary,
and tertiary systems.
But it’s sporadic...
It’s jumping around.
*Run diagnostics on all systems.*
*I want to know why my ship is acting up!*
Diagnostics aren’t working
either. I need your help fast
or we’re going to lose
environmental systems too!
On my way.
Mr. Thelin, you have the con.
Whoa! What just caused that?
I can’t nail it down.
Every time I try to
compensate for one system,
another one goes down.
This is getting us nowhere.
Agreed.
Let’s shut down all systems and
bring them back up under manual control.
We’ll route minimal power to
non-critical systems and lock
them down on a fixed setting.
Alright. Let’s do it.
That seems to have done
the trick... For the moment.
Congratulations, Chief.
Thanks.
Don’t get too comfortable though.
I want you to monitor
these systems constantly.
Advise me of anything
unusual. I’ll be on the bridge.
Aye, sir.
Why can’t I solve this? It’s all here...
I have all I need... I
must solve it... I must...
Captain Glenn?
And you are...?
Carter, Sir. Captain John T.
Carter of the USS Farragut.
I don’t remember inviting you!
Do you want to explain to
me why you fired on my ship?
Nonsense. I didn’t fire on anyone!
And I strongly suggest
that you leave my ship
before I’m forced to
deal with you personally!
What’s the big experiment,
Glenn? What are you doing here?
You wouldn’t understand!
RT?
He is tapped into those
devices orbiting Quorus Five.
They appear to be part of a network
of machines all working in concert.
But for what purpose, I can’t say.
Alright, that’s it Glenn.
You will relinquish
command to my Security Chief
and accompany me
peacefully to the Farragut.
The Azrael will then
follow us out of the system.
Go away!
I have important research
and I cannot be disturbed!
Let me try, sir.
Captain Glenn, it’s me, Henry Prescott.
Starfleet Academy training
mission to Altair Six?
You were my commanding
officer on that mission...
My only mission is
to solve this mystery!
And I don’t care who you are!
Mr. Prescott, Captain
Glenn is under arrest.
Take him into custody, please.
Aye, sir.
Captain Glenn, please come with me.
I... am not going anywhere.
Sorry, Mr. Prescott. I know it
must have been difficult to see
your former commanding officer
behaving behaving like that.
Yes, sir, it was.
Let’s get him back to the Farragut
and see if we can sort this out.
Translation, proofreading, subtitling
and synchronization: Mark Hildebrand