Where are you taking us?
To the brig, of course.
Now, Mr. Prescott!
Good aim, Commander.
Just because I’m a man of science
doesn’t mean I can’t handle a phaser.
Thanks, RT.
Carter here.
Just checking in, Jack.
Is everything alright over there?
It is now. We had a bit of an incident,
but everything’s under control.
Tell Doc Holley to stand by
to receive 3 priority patients.
Sir, Captain Glenn is gone.
He must have slipped away
while we were dealing with these guards.
Correction, prepare for
two priority patients.
We’ll be back momentarily. Carter out.
Any thoughts, RT?
It’s your hand, Jack. How
do you want to play it?
I’m more worried about what
Glenn has up his sleeve.
We don’t have time to track him down.
I’ll need you to start analyzing
Glenn’s data on those machines.
Judging by what we’ve seen already,
there isn’t much time.
I’m on it.
Mr. Prescott. I have a
feeling we’re going to need you
to execute that hostile
takeover plan we discussed.
Let’s go check on
your guard and get back
to the Farragut so you
can prepare your team.
Very well, sir!
Is it cold in here to you?
It does seem like they’ve
turned the heat down a bit.
Computer, increase the
temperature by ten degrees.
Why do you think these
guards were acting so bizarre?
That’s what I’m trying
to find out, Ensign.
Now if you’re through asking questions,
maybe you can assist me with
the analysis of this data.
Maybe I don’t want to help.
I was supposed to be
taking the day off anyway.
Are you refusing a direct
order from your superior?
What order? You said
“maybe” I could help you.
Well, “maybe” I don’t want to.
That’s true, you didn’t
actually order him.
I don’t think I’m going
to assist you anymore!
You can work out this
problem by yourself!
- What?!
- You heard me!
Ensign, you are relieved of
duty and confined to quarters!
Fine! See if you can do this without me!
What have you got, RT?
From the tone of your
message, it must be pretty big.
You bet it is, Jack.
Let’s have it.
Well, we’ve been correct
all along about one thing.
Those devices are drawing
the gases from the atmosphere
and using it as some sort of fuel.
The entire planet is
basically being turned
into a gigantic power source.
What in heaven’s name would anyone
need with such a huge power source?
My analysis concludes
multiple possibilities.
Things I never dreamed possible.
Things that could change Starfleet
and the human race forever.
I don’t follow.
There’s more. Captain Glenn
has successfully established
a remote connection to the
power generating mechanism.
And he’s attempting to activate it.
Can he do that? Does
he have the knowledge?
Not in his state of mind.
Well, I suppose there’s
a remote chance of
him hitting the right
combination, but not likely.
But if he tries?
The results could be
disastrous for everything
within a parsec of this system.
That’s all I need to know.
It’s imperative that we get both ships
as far away from this
planet as soon as possible.
- No!
- No?
We can’t leave yet.
Explain.
Maybe Glenn can’t activate
the device properly,
but I know I can. I must.
The scientific knowledge that
could be gained is enormous!
We can’t risk it.
I’m not going to abandon
this opportunity, Jack.
This is what I was meant for.
This is the reason I went into
sciences in the first place.
I have to see this through!
We’re going to take over the Azrael
and both ships are leaving
the system as soon as possible.
This experiment is concluded.
That’s an order, Mr. Tacket!
Noooo! I won’t let you!
Listen to yourself! Look at yourself!
This isn’t you, RT! Snap out of it!
Iím sorry. I donít
know what got into me.
It was like I wasn’t in control.
It’s that damned planet!
We’re getting out of here... right now.
Carter to Prescott.
*Prescott here.*
Have your security team
in the transporter room
on the double, armed and ready!
Transporter room, prepare
to beam security detail
to the Azrael bridge on my command.
Is it cold in here or what?
Sir, the Azrael has
raised their shields.
Confirmed. Looks like
Glenn still has some sense
of what’s going on around him.
Lt. Taylor, where are you going?
I’m taking a break.
Time for a swift cuppa
and a spot of lunch.
What’s it to you?!
Return to your station
immediately, mister!
I’m sorry, sir. I really
don’t know what came over me.
Mr. Thelin, I want a
precision attack on the Azrael.
Minimum force necessary to
bring down their shields.
As soon as they’re down,
cease fire immediately.
Maneuvering thrusters only.
Coming into position now, sir.
Evasive!
I can’t do it, sir. It’s too difficult.
Focus, Thelin! Stay on him!
Jack, I’m reading a build-up
of energy from the planet!
I’m aware of that, Robert!
Can someone turn up the damn heat
in here so I can concentrate?!
The Azrael shields are down!
Transporter room! Now!
The Azrael... it’s firing phasers
and photon torpedoes again!
Shields are at sixty percent!
Continue evasive maneuvers,
but don’t return fire!
Just keep us safe for
a few moments longer!
What are you doing here?!
Jones, take these
trespassers to the brig!
The Azrael has disarmed.
Carter to Prescott.
*Prescott here.*
I assume that the Azrael’s
crew was less than cooperative?
On the contrary, sir,
they were very cooperative.
*Well, don’t just stand there.*
*Get that ship moving and
follow us out of the system.*
Aye, sir.
Energy build-up is almost complete!
Get us out of here! Warp factor six!